이전 AMC 워킹데드에서는...
Previously on AMC's The Walking Dead...
종착역이야
Terminus...
내일 우린 종착역으로 간 다음
Tomorrow we go to the end of the line.
그리고 워싱턴으로 갈겁니다
Then, Washington.
사랑한다 리지야...
I love you, Lizzie.
당신은 머무를 필요 없어요
You don't need to stay.
우린 머무를 수 없어요
We can't stay.
만약을 대비하는거야
Just in case...
종착역에 오신걸 환영합니다.
Welcome to Terminus!
트레일러 안으로 들어가! 당장!
Go to the train car. Now!
릭?
Rick!
곧 저놈들이 스스로 꽤나 바보 짓을 했다고 느끼게 될겁니다
They're gonna feel pretty stupid
when they find out
저새끼들이 건들면 좆되는 사람을 건드렸다는 것 말이죠
they screwed with the wrong people.
( woman screaming )
( whimpering )
알렉스: 그 표지판을 세우는 짓은 하면 안 되는 거였어
Alex: We should never
have put up the signs.
무슨 생각으로 표지판을 세웠던거야?
What the hell did we
think was gonna happen?
우리가 그들을 데려온거야
We brought them here.
우린 좋은 것을 하려고 했던거야
We were trying
to do something good.
- ( laughs )
- 우린 정상적인 사람들이었잖아
- We were being human beings.
지금 우린 어떤사람들인데 게리스?
What are we now, Gareth?
( woman screaming )
( radio chatter )
아브라함: 그들은 좋은 사람으로 보였지만,
우리는 우리 길을 갈 준비가 되어 있었어
Abraham: They seemed nice
enough, but I was ready to go.
하지만 우린 여기에 머물렀지, 씨팔
We just got here, but, damn,
우리 길을 갈 시간이었는데
it was time to go.
그들에게 워싱턴에 대해 말할 때
When I told them about DC,
책임자 새끼의 대가리에서
나온 윙크와 끄덕임,
a wink and a nod from
the head asshole in charge,
그들은 총을 꺼냈지
그때 우리는 계획대로
they pulled their guns
and it was right back
가야 할 시간이었는데...
결국 개판이 됐지만...
to our regularly scheduled
shitstorm.
사샤: 혹시 여기 들어오기전에 타이리스 봤나요?
Sasha: Before they put you in
here, you didn't see Tyreese?
- 미숀: 아니요
- 사샤 : 다행이네요
- Michonne: No.
- Sasha: Good.
데릴: 하얀 십자가가 그려진 검은색 차였어
Daryl: Black car with a
white cross painted on it.
따라 가려고 했어
결국 놓쳤지만
I tried to follow it.
I tried.
메기: 베스는 살아있었어?
Maggie:
But she's alive?
데릴: 살아있었어
Daryl:
She's alive.
( radio chatter continues )
( men chatting )
남자: 뭐하는 짓이야?
Man:
What are you doing?
모두 입다물고있어
Everybody shut up.
닥쳐!
Shut up!
좋아, 네명이 우리쪽으로 오고있어
All right, got four of them
pricks coming our way.
우린 뭘 해야하는지 알고있어
Y'all know what to do.
먼저 눈을 공격하고
Go for their eyes first.
그 다음 목을 공격하는거야
Then their throats.
남자: 등을 한쪽 벽에 밀착시켜라, 지금 당장!
Man: Put your backs to the walls
on either side of the car now.
( footsteps on roof )
피해!!
Move!
( doors opening )
( gas mask hissing )
( grunts )
( saw buzzing )
잠깐 기다려
Okay, hold up.
다 됐군
All right.
( whimpering )
( muffled screaming )
- ( knife slices )
- ( blood pouring )
이봐, 몇명째 조지고 있는거야?
Hey, guys. What were
your shot counts?
- 38
- ( thuds )
- 38.
Gareth: 이봐!
Gareth:
Hey!
몇명째 조지고 있는거냐고
Your shot count?
젠장, 죄송합니다.
Crap, man, I'm sorry.
처음 도축하는거라서요..
It was my first roundup.
다 조진다음에,
사무실쪽으로가서
After you're done here,
go back to your point
몇명 조졌는지 세어봐
and count the shells.
내일까지 아줌마는 시체들을 모으지 않을거야
Kaylee won't be gathering
them until tomorrow.
( muffled ) 이봐요
( muffled ) Hey.
말 좀 하게 이것좀 풀어줘요
Hey, let me talk to you.
A 트레일러에서 4명, D 트레일러에서 4명?
Four from A, four from D?
남자: 맞아요
Man:
Yeah.
이봐요, 잠깐만 말 할 수 있게 해줘요
Hey, let me talk
to you for a minute.
말 할 수 있게 해달라구요
Let me talk to you for a minute.
- 잠깐 동안 대화 좀 하자구요
- 왜?
- Let me talk to you for a minute.
- What?
저희를 죽이지마세요
아직 상황을 좋은 쪽으로 바꿀 수 있어요
Don't do this.
We can fix this.
- 아니, 불가능해
- 이럴 필요까진 없잖아요!!
- No, you can't.
- You don't have to do this.
우리가 이 상황을 해결할 수 있는 방법을 알려줬잖아요
We told you there's a way
out of all this.
당신들은 기회를 잡는거라구요
You just have to take a chance.
이 상황을 멈추게 하는 방법을 아는 남자를 안다구요
We have a man
who knows how to stop it.
그는 치료법을 알아요
그를 워싱턴으로 보내야 한다구요
He has a cure. We just have
to get him to Washington.
이럴 필요 없다구요 게리스
You don't have to do this, man.
우린 세상을 원래 모습으로 돌릴 수 있다구요
We can put the world
back to how it was.
돌아 갈 수 없어
Can't go back, Bob.
할 수 있다고!
이럴 필요 없다니까!
We can!
You don't have to do this!
아까 우리는
당신이 가방을 가지고 나무쪽으로 가는 것 봤어
We saw you go into
the woods with a bag
그리고 그걸 두고 온 것을 알지
and come out without it.
그리고 가방을 찾기 위해, 정찰꾼을 보냈지만
찾지 못했지
Had to pull my spotters back
before we could go look for it.
가방에 뭐가 들은거야?
What was in it?
무기를 숨겼지, 안그래?
You hid it, right?
상황이 안 좋아졌을때를 대비해서
In case things went bad?
영리하군
Smart.
우린 가방을 찾을거야
Still, we'll find it.
하지만 지금 찾으러 나가기엔 밖이 너무 위험하지
But it's too dangerous
to go out there right now.
가방에 뭐가 들었지?
What was in it?
매우 궁금하군
I'm curious.
가방이 참 컸는데 말이야
And it was a big bag.
내가 밥을 죽이길 원하는거야?
You really gonna let me do this?
좋아, 날 밖으로 풀어줘
Well, let me take you out there.
가방을 찾아서 보여줄게
I'll show you.
그럴일 없다는 거 알잖아
Not gonna happen.
This might.
릭: 가방안엔 총이 들어있어
Rick:
There's guns in it.
AK-47
AK-47.
44 매그넘
.44 Magnum.
자동장전 무기들
야간투시경
Automatic weapons.
Nightscope.
합성 활도 있고
There's a compound bow
붉은 손잡이의 마체테도 있지
*마체테: 날이 넓고 무거운 칼
and a machete with a red handle.
너희들을 죽여버릴 무기들이지
That's what I'm gonna
use to kill you.
( chuckles )
( sighs )
고마워
Thanks.
저 놈들을 건조기에 넣는 것까지 두시간 남았다
You have two hours
to get them on the driers.
두시간 뒤에 돌아올거야
I'm gonna go back
to public face.
신나게 저 놈들을 조질 시간이다
Now's the time we can get messy,
해가 지기전까지 모든 것을 끝내야해
but we need to dial
it all in by sundown.
- 알겠습니다
- 네
- Got it.
- Yes, sir.
( gunshots )
척, 무슨일이야?
Hey, Chuck?
( gunshot )
( rumbling )
( theme music playing )
Korean subtitle made by Working Dead(Bae), for My Dog, Austin.
made this subtitle. 2014-10-13
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
거의 다 왔네요
We're close.
거기에 쥬디스 그리고 당신과 함께 간 다음에
I'm gonna get you both there.
쥬디스와 당신을 안전하게 만들어줄거에요
Make sure you're safe.
( baby coos )
그리고 난 그곳에 머무르지 않을거에요
But I'm not gonna stay.
( snarling )
( crying )
전 못 해요
I can't.
Not yet.
우린 죽일 수 있어야만 해요
You're going to have
to be able to.
( snarling )
( whispers ) 존나 많아요
( whispers ) More.
( snarling )
( gunshots )
( gunshots continue )
저 총소리들,
That gunfire,
아마도 종착역쪽에서 나는 것일 수도 있어요
it could have been
from Terminus.
누군가 그들을 공격하고 있던 것 같아요
Someone was attacking them.
또는 그들이 누군가를 공격하고 있었겠죠
Or they were attacking someone.
아직도 종착역에 가고싶나요?
Do we even want to find out?
네
Yeah.
거기에 동쪽으로 가는 또다른 길이 있을거에요
There's another track due east.
종착역에서 그 길을 찾을 거고
우리는 정말 안전해질거에요
It'll get us there.
We'll be real careful.
우리는 답을 알 수 있을거에요
We're gonna get answers.
라디오 속 여자: 10분 남았어
Woman on radio:
10-minute count.
터트린다음에 조심해야해, 마틴
You screw up,
you're on your own, Martin.
걱정해줄 필요없어
난 알아서 잘하잖아
You don't have to tell me.
I wipe my own ass.
알렉스는 그러지 못했지만
Alex didn't get it.
이봐, 난 검을 가진 여자가 골칫덩어리라고 생각해
See, I knew the chick
with the sword was bad news.
그 년은 그냥 자체가 무기처럼 보이지
Bitch looked like a weapon
with a weapon.
He was always
a sloppy-ass mother.
맞아, 난 알버트한테 그들을 조진다음에 꼬마애 모자를
달라고 말했어
Yeah, I told Albert I want the kid's
hat after they bleed him out.
무전기 버튼에서 손 때
Keep your finger off
the button and drop it.
그들은 총 8명을 조질거야
They're only doing eight
before public face.
이봐요, 이럴 필요 없어요
Listen, y'all don't
have to do this.
당신들이 무엇을 원하든지,
우리는 누구나 환영받는 곳을 가지고 있다구요
Whatever you want, we got a
place where everyone's welcome.
- 닥쳐, 새끼야
- 네
- Shut up, man.
- Okay.
우린 너가 말한 검을 가진 여자의 친구들이야
We're friends of
the chick with the sword
그리고 모자 쓴 꼬마도 우리의 친구지
and the kid in the hat.
그들은 우릴 공격했고,
우린 단지 그들을 가둔 것뿐이에요
They attacked us.
We're just holding them.
당신 말 안 믿어
I don't believe you.
누굴 더 붙잡아 둔거지?
붙잡아 둔 사람들 이름 알고있나?
Who else do you have?
Do you know their names?
그 꼬마와 사무라이 여자, 그 사람들이 전부에요
We just have the boy
and the samurai, that's it.
우린 단지 그들을 보호해주고 있는 거라구요
We were just
protecting ourselves.
당신 말 안 믿는다고
I don't believe you.
그 곳에 꽤 많은 우리 사람들이 있어요
There's a bunch of us out there
여섯 방향으로 포진해 있죠
in six different directions.
종착역에서 많은 총성이있었고
There was a lot
of gunfire back home.
우린 동시에 폭죽을 터트려야만해요
We need to set off our
charges all at the same time
워커를 교란시키는 건
당신들에게도 좋은거라구요.
to confuse the dead ones away.
That's good for you, too.
아니, 안 좋아
No, it isn't.
지금 워커 떼가 종착역쪽으로 향하고 있어
There's a herd heading
toward Terminus right now.
워커들을 교란시킬 필요 없다는거지
We don't want
to confuse them away.
우린 그들의 도움이 필요할거야
We're gonna need their help.
그곳은 단순한 곳이 아니에요
It's a compound.
그들은 당신이 오는 걸 확인할거에요
They'll see you coming.
설사 당신이 워커떼에 섞여서
If you even make it that far
그곳으로 접근한다해도 당신을 확인할거에요
with all the cold
bodies heading over.
캐롤
Carol.
어떻게 하실거에요?
How are you gonna do this?
다 조져버려야죠
I'm gonna kill people.
아기 이름이 뭡니까
She got a name?
이봐요, 아기 이름이 뭐에요
Hey, she got a name?
주디스
Judith.
당신의 딸인가요? 아니면..?
She your daughter or something?
그냥 친구에요
She's a friend.
아하
Huh.
( sighs )
전 친구가 없어요
I don't have any friends.
제 말은,아는 사람은 있지만
그들은 단지 같이 살고 있는 사람이라는거에요
I mean, I know people. They're
just assholes I stay alive with.
아까 그 여자도 당신 친구인가요?
The other one your friend?
The woman?
저도 친구들이 있었죠
I used to have them.
일요일마다 같이 풋볼을 보곤했죠
Used to watch
football on Sundays.
교회에도 가곤 했죠
( laughs )
Went to church.
예전에 있었던 일이지만
I know I did.
더 이상 머리속에 그릴 수 없어요
But I can't picture it anymore.
시간 가는 줄 모를 정도로 즐거웠던 시간들이죠
It's funny how you don't
even notice the time go by.
하지만
그 후에 개 같은것들이 세상에 쌓이기 시작했죠
Horrible shit just stacks
up day after day.
당신은 그 개 같은거에 익숙해있겠죠
You get used to it.
난 그 개좆 같은거에 익숙해지지 않았어
I haven't gotten used to it.
물론이죠, 익숙해지지 않았죠
당신은 아기들을 구해주는 착한 사람이니까요
Of course you haven't. You're the
kind of guy who saves babies.
그건 마치 닻을 보호하는 것과 같죠
It's kind of like
saving an anchor
당신이 바다 한가운데에 보트 없이
갇혔을 경우에 말이에요
when you're stuck without a boat
in the middle of the ocean.
어떤 벽을 등지고서 ,안 그래요?
Been behind some kind
of walls, right?
당신은 여태 자신의 손을 더럽히지 않았죠
You're still around, but you haven't
had to get your hands dirty.
그게 사실이죠
I can tell.
이봐요, 당신은 좋은 사람이에요
See, you're a good guy.
당신은 내가 어떤 짓을 해왔는지 좆도몰라요
You have no idea about
the things I've done.
좋은 사람이라는 건 알아요
You're a good guy.
그게 당신이 오늘 죽을 이유죠
That's why you're
gonna die today.
또한 그 아기가 죽을 이유이죠
It's why the baby
is going to die.
또는..
Or...
당신은 밖에 있는 차를 타고
you can get in that car,
여기서 벗어나서
get out of here,
계속 살아 남을 수 있죠
keep on being lucky.
날 죽일 수 있을거라고 생각하나?
You think you're gonna kill me?
왜 날 죽이지 않고 살려두는거죠?
Why haven't you killed me?
제가 살아서 어떻게 당신을 도울 수 있겠어요?
How does having
me alive help you?
도대체 왜 날 살려두면서 나랑 대화하는거에요?
Why the hell are you
even talking to me?
아기를 데리고, 차에 타서
Take her, take the car,
그냥 가세요
and go.
오늘 사람을 죽이고 싶지 않다구요
I don't want to do this today.
( walks snarling )
남자: 등을 한쪽 벽에 밀착시켜라, 지금 당장!
Man: Put your backs to the wall
on either side of the car now.
( snarling )
( shouting )
( gunshots )
- 종착역에서 나는 소린가요?
- 그래
- Is that Terminus?
- Yeah.
그런 것 같아
Probably.
아마도 당신 친구들이 이긴 것 같네요
Maybe you're gonna win this.
아니면 아마도 당신 친구가...
Maybe your friend--
제 말은, 아마도 그 여자가
I mean, maybe that woman
잡혔을 수도 있다는 거죠
just got capped.
그녀가 다시 돌아왔을 때,
아마 나는 포로가 될 지도 모르죠
Maybe I'm gonna be the one who
gets capped when she comes back.
오늘 아무도 죽지 않을거야
Nobody's got to die today.
( scoffs )
이봐요, 만약 그렇게 믿고있다면...
Man, if you believe that...
정확히 당신과 아기는 살아 남을 수 없을거에요
then it's definitely
gonna be you and the kid.
비록 저 곳이 완전 불타버려서
아무것도 남지 않게 되어도 말이죠
Even if that place
is burning to the ground.
( gunfire )
라디오 속 남자: 이봐, 무슨일이야?
Man on radio:
Hey, what the hell was that?
내 말 들려?
Do you copy?
- 너넨 여기에 있어
- 가레스, 얘네들은 움직일 수 없어
- You stay here.
- Gareth, these guys aren't going anywhere.
그냥 닥치고 여기에 있어!
무슨일인지 확인하기 전까지
Stay here until
I know what's happening.
남자: 그냥 여기에 앉아있어야해?
Man:
So we just sit here?
일이나 하자
Got a job to do.
( grunting )
( gunfire continues )
( gasping )
( snarling )
오 씨부랄.. 신이시여
Oh, Jesus.
( snarling )
( screaming )
- 가레스, 내 말 들려?
- 아마 바쁠거야
- You there, Gareth?
- He's busy.
가스 냄새 못 맡았어?
You smell the smoke?
총 소리 못 들었냐고,
그가 죽었을 수도 있어
You hear the shots?
He could be dead.
여기서 우린 뭘하고 있는거야?
밖은 개판이란 말이야
The hell we doing here? The
whole place could be going up.
너가 무슨일이 일어났는지 보러간다면
그건 절차를 무너뜨리는거야
You went on one roundup
and you blew protocol.
우린 보안쪽 일을 하는게 아니라고
그건 우리 일이 아니야
We don't deal with security.
That ain't our job.
이게 우리일이라고
이봐, 날 봐
This is.
Hey, look at me.
뭐?
What?
No, no, no, no, no!
글렌: 릭!
Glenn:
Rick!
도대체 뭔 개좆같은일이 일어난거야?
What the hell is going on?
- 미숀: 누군가 그들을 친 것 같아
- 아마 우리 사람들이 풀려났을 수도 있지
- Michonne: Someone hit them.
- Maybe our people got free.
잠시만요
Excuse me.
뭐하려고?
What the hell are you doing?
아마도 제가 이 껍질을 이용해서
문을 딸 수도 있을 것 같아요
I might be able to use this
shell to compromise the door.
밖에 소리를 들어보면, 문을 열어줄 수 있는
사람은 아무도 없는 것 같아요
From the sound of things, there may
not be anybody left to open it.
유진, 미안하지만 그냥 닥쳐주세요
Eugene, I'm sorry, but shut up.
- 그래
- 이봐
- Okay.
- Hey.
아버지가 돌아올 거에요
My dad's gonna be back.
- 나머지 분들도요
- 그래
- They all are.
- They are.
우린 그들이 싸울 때 함께 싸울 수 있게 준비를
하고 있어야해
And we need to get ready to fight
our way out with them when they do.
( snarling )
( woman screaming )
( gunfire continues )
( screaming )
( gunshot )
( snarling )
만약 그들에게 문제가 생겼다면,
우리는 기회를 얻은거야
If they got problems,
we got a chance.
마치 폭탄 소리 같았어요
It sounded like a bomb.
좆 같은 전쟁 소리처럼 들렸지
Sounds like a damn war.
그래
Right there.
여기 사람들은 도대체 뭐하는 새끼들이야?
What the hell are these people?
사람새끼도 아닌 새끼들이지
They ain't people.
하지마세요
그냥 변하게 내버려두세요
Don't.
Let him turn.
밖에 나가서, 있는 사람들을 다 조져버려
Cross any of these
people, you kill them.
망설이지마
Don't hesitate.
They won't.
( gunfire continues )
( man shouting )
릭: 우리는 달려서 저 곳까지 갈 수있을거야
Rick: If we run, we
can get by them.
그들은 워커들에게 정신이 팔려있어
They're distracted.
저 안에 있는 사람들을 꺼내줘야해
We got to let those people out.
그들은 우리와 같은 사람일거야
That's still who we are.
꺼내줘야해
It's got to be.
남자: 도와주세요!
Man:
Help me!
( shouting continues )
빨리 열어
Come on, come on, come on.
우린 같은 사람이야!
우린 같다고!
We're the same!
We're them!
물러서!
Back off!
( laughs ) 우린 같은 사람이야
( laughs ) We're the same.
( snarling )
Come on.
( grunting )
( water dripping )
( gunfire )
( gunfire continues )
- 우린 돌아가야 해요
- 릭: A구역은 저 방향이야
- We got to double back.
- Rick: A is that way.
우린 돌아가야해요,
우리가 어디에 있는지도 모르잖아요
We go back, we don't
know where we are.
그래,
우린 정말 선택권이 없지, 안그래?
We don't really
have a choice, do we?
( gunshots )
- 여기서 기다려
- 릭. 릭!
- Wait here.
- Rick. Rick!
( snarling )
남자: 재장전!
Man:
Reloading!
( groans )
( walkers snarling )
( screaming )
다른 길로 돌아가야겠어
We're going to have
to double back.
( gunfire continues )
무기 버리고 돌아서!
Drop your weapons
and turn around.
네 면상 좀 보자
I want to see your face.
( walkers snarling )
빨리!
Now!
( grunting )
Ah!
( panting )
표지판들...
The signs...
그건 진짜였어..
they were real.
여긴 안식처였어
It was a sanctuary.
하지만 사람들이 왔고 이 곳을 차지했지
People came and took this place.
- 닥치고 우리 사람들이 어디..
- 그리고 그들은 사람들을 강간했고 죽였지
- Just tell me where--
- And they raped and they killed
그리고 웃었어
and they laughed
몇주동안
over weeks.
하지만 우린 밖으로 나왔어
But we got out
우린 싸웠고
우린 다시 되찾았지
and we fought
and we got it back.
그리고 우린 그 메시지를 들었지
And we heard the message.
"너희는 도살자이다..."
You're the butcher...
그렇지않으면 "너희는 도살되는 소이다"
or you're the cattle.
트레일러칸 안에서 밖으로 끌려나온
사람들 어디있어?
The men they pulled from that
train car, where are they?
- ( screams )
- 어디있냐고 이 소 같은년아
- Where are they?
( groaning )
지금...
Now...
내 머리를 향해 조준해
point it at my head.
( laughs )
넌 우리 중 한명이 될 수 있었어
You could have been one of us.
세상이 너에게 말하는 것을 들을 수 있었다고
You could have listened to
what the world is telling you.
사람들을 여기로 끌어온 다음
그들의 물건을 빼앗고 죽였지?
You lead people here and you take
what they have and you kill them?
여기가 그 지랄을 하던 곳이지?
Is that what this place is?
아니, 처음에는 그렇지 않았어
No, not at first.
그건 마땅히 해야만 되는 것이었지
It's what it had to be.
우린 여전히 여기에 있어
And we're still here.
아니, 너는 여기에 없어
You're not here.
나도 마찬가지야
Neither am I.
( snarling )
안돼..!! 안돼!!!!!!!!
No! No! No!
오! 안돼,! 신이시여!
Oh! No, God!
No! No!
( walkers snarling )
물러서!
Back off!
( crying )
물러서!
Back off!
무기를 바닥 위에 버리고,
Put your weapons on the ground.
무기를 앞으로 차, 당장
당장!
Kick them over right now.
Right now!
타이리스: 제발
Tyreese:
Please.
제발, 하지마
아기를 내버려둬
Please, don't.
Don't hurt her.
( crying )
밖으로 나가
Go outside.
밖으로 나가라고!
Go outside!
목 꺾이는 거 보고싶지않으면 나가라고
Just one twist, man.
- 안돼!
- 날 그렇게 만들지말라고!
- Don't!
- Don't make me!
( crying )
밖으로 나가
Go outside.
알겠어
All right.
- ( snarling )
- ( screaming )
신시아, 들려?
Cynthia, do you copy?
( static hissing )
신시아, 대답해
Cynthia, do you copy?
- ( pounding )
- ( Tyreese grunting )
( pounding stops )
( fussing )
( grunts )
그래
이게 정상이지
Yeah.
That's how it works.
난 죽이지 않을거야
I won't.
( grunts )
- ( grunts )
- 죽이지 않을거라고!
- I won't!
죽이지 않을거라고!
I won't!
- ( blows landing )
- 타이리스:죽이지 않을거라고!
- Tyreese: I won't!
죽이지 않을거라고!
I won't!
( gunfire continues )
치료제가 뭐에요, 유진?
What's the cure, Eugene?
그건 기밀사항이야
It's classified.
우린 무슨일이 일어나고 있는지 몰라
We don't know
what's gonna happen.
아브라함: 유진을 그냥 내버려두세요
Abraham:
You leave him be.
- 우린, 우리 할일을 계속해야해
- 그래, 하지만 치료제가 무엇인지 들을 때가 왔어
- We need to keep working.
- Yeah, but it's time to hear it.
다음 계획이 뭔지 모르기 때문이지
'Cause we don't know
what's coming next.
다음 계획은 여기서 나가는 거에요
What's next
is we get out of this.
설사 내가 당신에게 모든 걸 말했어도,
Even if I told you all,
그리고, 단계별 안내서를 제공했었더라도
even if I provided
step-by-step instructions
잘 짜여진 질문들 그리고 설명들이 필요했기 때문에
complete with illustrations
and a well-composed FAQ
난 그것을 위해 레드윙에 갔었고
and I went red-ring,
그 치료제는 나와 함께 죽었을 겁니다.
the cure would still
die with me.
일이 그렇게 되게 내버려 두지 않을거야
I'm not gonna let that happen.
가장 좋은 시나리오는,
우리가 그 개같은 곳에서 빠져나가는 것이었어요
The best-case scenario,
we step out into a hellstorm
총알들, 화마, 그리고 워커들로 부터요
of bullets, fire, and walkers.
저는 걸음이 빠르지 않죠
I'm not fleet of foot.
I sure as hell can't take
a dead one down
with sharp buttons
and hella confidence.
그래, 하지만 우린 할 수 있고 그렇게 할 거야
Yeah, but we can and we will.
당신은 우리에게 아무것도 빚지지 않았지
You don't owe us anything.
아직까지
Not yet.
우린 단지 그게 무엇인지 듣고 싶을 뿐이야
But we just want to hear it.
그럴 필요 없어
You don't have to.
난 10명으로 이루어진 팀에 소속되어 있었어요
I was part
of a 10-person team
질병을 무기화하기 위한 인간 게놈 프로젝트에서
at the Human Genome Project
to weaponize diseases
무기화된 질병에 맞서기 위한 것이었죠
to fight weaponized diseases.
병원균 미생물들을 연구하고 있었고
Pathogenic microorganisms
with pathogenic microorganisms.
매우 열정적이었죠
Fire with fire.
여러 부처가 관련되어 있었고
Interdepartmental
drinks were had,
공유된 정보와 함께 여러 관계들이 존재했죠
relationships made,
information shared.
저는 모든 세부사항을 알고 있어요
I am keenly aware
of all the details
fail-safe delivery systems 뒤에 숨겨진 세부사항이죠
* fail-safe delivery systems : 실패했을 경우를 대비한 체계
behind fail-safe
delivery systems
이 지구상에 모든 살아있는 사람들을 죽이기 위한 거죠
to kill every living
person on this planet.
저는 워싱턴 DC안에서 약간의 계획의
틀어짐이 있었다고 믿어요
I believe with a little tweaking
on the terminals in DC,
우리는 그걸 되돌릴 수 있죠
we can flip the script.
Take out every last
dead one of them.
Fire with fire.
All things being equal,
it does sound pretty badass.
이제 우리 할일을 하죠
So let's get back to work.
( banging )
나와! 펜스쪽으로 가자
Come on!
Fight to the fence!
남자: 그의 곁에서 멀리 떨어지지마!
Man:
Do not leave his side!
- 가자!
- 칼!
- Go, go, go!
- Carl!
빨리와
가자!
Come on.
Let's go!
올라가서 넘어가!
Up and over.
움직여!
Let's go! Move!
남자: 어서 움직여!
Man:
Let's go! Move!
여자: 빨리와!
Woman:
Come on!
여기야
Right here.
아브라함: 안가고 여기서 뭐하는거야?
Abraham: The hell are we
still around here for?
릭: 총, 그리고 나머지 보급품들
Rick:
Guns, some supplies.
펜스를 따라간다음
이 무기들을 사용해서
Go along the fences.
Use the rifles.
남은 놈들을 죽이자
Take out the rest of 'em.
뭐라구요?
What?
그들은 살아남으면 안돼
They don't get to live.
릭, 우린 빠져나왔어
모두 끝난거야
Rick, we got out.
It's over.
아직 안 끝났어 안에 있는 사람들이 죽을때까진
It's not over till
they're all dead.
무슨 소리하는거야
저 안은 총알이 날아다니고
The hell it isn't.
That place is on fire.
워커들로 가득차있어
Full of walkers.
아브라함: 난 이 쓸때없는 짓을 하지 않을거야
Abraham: I'm not dicking
around with this crap.
우린 빠져 나왔잖아
We just made it out.
펜스는 무너져있어
The fences are down.
그들은 도망가거나 죽을거야
They'll run or die.
( laughs )
당신이 우릴 구해준 겁니까?
Did you do that?
( laughs )
나를 따라오세요
You have to come with me.
( crying )
주디스, 무사했구나
Judith. You're okay.
( sobbing )
( no audible dialogue )
( Judith crying )
무슨일 있었어요?
What happened?
여기로 워커들이 들이닥쳤어요
There were a bunch
of walkers out here
그리고 그가 그의손으로 주디스의 목을 감고 있었어요
and he got his hands
around Judith's neck.
그는 죽었어요
No, he's dead.
제가.. 그래야만 했어요
I-- I had to.
당신처럼요
So I did.
할 수 있었어요
I could.
저 곳에 불길이 여전히 타고있는지
확신이 안가네요
I don't know if
the fire is still burning.
불이 꺼졌네요
It is.
그래요. 이제 가야겠어요
Yeah. We need to go.
데릴: 그래, 근데 어디로 가게?
Daryl:
Yeah, but where?
일단 저 곳으로부터 멀리가야지
Somewhere far away from there.
우린 그와 할 얘기가 있어
We'll talk to him.
하지만 지금은 아니야
Not just yet.
( whimpering )
알렉스: 엄마! 엄마, 제 옆으로 오세요
Alex:
Mom! Mom, come on.
( gasping )
여자: 안돼!
Woman:
No!
남자: 저 년이 좋겠어
Man:
That one.
안돼, 제발요
또 그러지마세요
No, no, please.
Not again.
( sobbing )
안돼... 안돼!!
No! No!
진정하세요
괜찮아요
It's okay.
- 괜찮을거에요
- ( shrieks )
- It's okay.
아니.. 너넨 좆된거야..
No, it's not.
( chuckles )
( screams )
( door shuts )
다시 되찾을 거에요
We're gonna take it back.
어떻게 하려고?
How?
우린 해내고 말거에요
We will.
"너희는 도살자, 혹은 소 중에 하나란다"
You're either the butcher
or the cattle.
오..!
Oh.
잘 보셨나요. 미흡하지만 양해부탁드립니다.
퀄리티는 떨어지지만 업로드 속도로 승부보겠습니다.
Sync & corrections by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com